I can press the button whenever I want,
whenever it feels right. I [music] don't
tend to look at the competition that
much. Like I really look at, you know,
what can we do uniquely well and what
are our values and like, you know, how
do we maximally [music] accelerate
towards that? You know, maybe a year or
two these speeds will become, you know,
maybe if not the default, like very
close to the default. And you look at
the cost of Luna, right? It's
phenomenal. Technology has a way to
become like, you know, very, very
efficient over time. [music] We're very
focused on like, you know, very broad
access and we're optimizing for, you
know, the utility that you get out of it
directly. [music] I heard there's an
actual physical button now.
>> Yes, Deris.
>> I will show it to you. It's like [music]
very very cool.
>> Tibo, thank you so much for joining me.
>> Of course. Yeah, glad to be here.
>> Yes, really excited to talk to you. I
want to actually start with your time at
Google. So you were on the deep mind
team and before chat GPT Google had
something called LM chat and you had
tweeted uh Google was too nervous to
release it. Deep mind was blocked from
shipping products that could disrupt
Google and I think about that a lot.
What were you thinking at that time
while you were working on these products
that was you know well before uh chat
GPT really changed the world.
>> Yeah it was a very exciting time. So um
deep mind was a very creative place. I
was mostly focused on um my specialty
was infrastructure and products for to
accelerate research. And so there was
there was obviously a group working on
language models uh and scaling that. And
then they had like gotten pretty good
results and then it was like a natural
thing to think about hey you know can
you turn that into something that you
know you can chat to and you know can
use um you know for various things. And
so then naturally like the idea of like
something like LM chat sort of emerges
um and then it was internal and then
there was sort of this ambition to um
make it into a publicly available uh
tool.
>> What year was this?
>> And this was it was like a year before
Chhatra roughly.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and then but we were also building
all sorts of other things that I'm not
going to talk about but it was a very
creative place. Uh and then just deep
mind was not set up to ship product. uh
is open AI is a very very different
place in that sense. Um we just like
research and products just collaborate
super closely together. We ideate
together. We co-design a lot of things.
We have a big bias to ship uh and uh
also a big bias towards you know making
things available for people which I
really love and this is sort of like
what uh drove me here the mission the
people um the talent density. I mean
there's so many great things about open
eye really. Did you know at the time
where you were involved in LM chat that
that was something special or would
become something special?
>> It it felt it felt very special like the
models were you know it's sort of like
the first time um you know you realized
like you could get coherent text and you
know something helpful. Initially it was
more funny than helpful and then
gradually it became more and more
helpful.
>> So you say you think about that often
and I I understand that I think you know
in a lot of ways Google got in their own
way. um what are some of the lessons
that you learned there that you took to
OpenAI?
>> Yeah, so this is why I think about it
often. I I think about it in terms of
like the culture that I have on the team
uh the culture of OpenAI itself and so
like the good parts to preserve and like
you know what not to do. Um, OpenAI has
a very bottoms up uh culture. Like it's
a very empowering culture. Like people
can come up with all sorts of ideas and
get together and then very very quickly
ship something and there's very little
stop energy uh in general for like new
product ideas which is exhilarating and
fun and you know it's all about
impacting the world in positive ways. Uh
and so preserving that is very important
to me. The other thing that is also
important is like to not make it a mess,
right? So you don't want to have like a
hodgepodge of like no features and like
no overall direction and coherence and
so it's counterbalanced with the sense
of um simplicity and you being proud
about the quality of the product. Uh I
think the chat GBT iOS app is like you
know one of the best apps out there. Uh
and so we want we want to keep that. Uh
we're investing a lot in you know things
like delight performance efficiency
simplicity. So there's these overall
principles while still empowering
everyone everyone to like try new things
and ship very quickly.
>> If you were to give advice to a founder
about how to develop that kind of
culture uh like what are some of the
more tangible elements or practices that
occur inside OpenAI that can kind of
gives give advice uh to a founder? Yes,
I think having having conviction um and
finding a way to be to have users and
iterate very quickly from feedback and
then also uh being willing to disrupt
yourself that is not as much relevant
for founder but is relevant for you know
companies like openi like we come up
with new research new ideas all the time
and being able to identify when is the
right moment to go and invest in them
even though it means like maybe
reallocating resources from you know the
main gig
uh super important but it's very hard
but it's super important to be able to
do that.
>> Yeah. I mean that's the exact thing that
you were describing at Google. They kind
of weren't able to do that. Um that's
great. I mean does that
>> they have a plan to be fair. It's like
you know it was all it was all part of a
big plan. Um but to me it wasn't it
wasn't uh it wasn't the right place. at
at OpenAI or or any company as it
matures does that become more difficult
to maintain that kind of culture of
shipping and willingness to disrupt
yourself especially when you you know if
you have a cash cow just printing money
and you have this other new thing over
here that might be something cool and
innovative. We are a very very
forward-looking um and the the the
future of AI and what it will all look
like and how humanity benefits doesn't
really wait or doesn't really care for
you know whatever you have established
here you know over the next month or 3
months and so you know I think it's very
important to lean in um and to you know
just be like openeyed about where it's
all going
>> and then you know figure out like how to
position yourself. So that you know you
you you do catch that wave. Um you know
even even for open it's like we we train
models and then we discover their
capabilities like we don't benchmarks
don't tell you everything. We have to
play quite a bit with the models
themselves to sort of like realize uh
it's like oh you know maybe we haven't
thought about you know benefiting from
it in like this specific way or like oh
it can do this. Um and then you're
you're just like oh that I mean that's a
shift in like you know how we think
about the product. for example, like
right now like you know we we we
launched the new voice uh voice and it's
super delightful to talk to. Uh it's
very natural now. It's capable of tool
use as well.
>> Yeah.
>> And that changes things like now I spend
a lot more time just talking to it. Um
another thing I I do all the time is
like dictation because the quality of
the dictation is like so so good and
it's like much more efficient as a as a
way instead of like typing the prompt.
And so in the morning I just like I sit
there with my phone and I'm like blah
blah blah. It's just like you know
couple of things to do for charge and um
and then it just goes and like does it
it has access to all my tools.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and that is like that was not
possible before we had like really good
voice models and so that completely
changes in suddenly how you think about
the product.
>> Yeah. Let's continue talking about new
models, new harnesses. Um a few weeks
ago I'm going to start with another one
of your tweets because you know these
are bangers. Uh [laughter] codeex will
seem primitive in two to three months.
We're about to go through another major
evolution. The next generation of models
need more than your laptop. Um, what
areas, let's start with the harness
first. What areas of the harness are
still ripe for innovation as a model
gets better?
>> Yeah, so many so many. Um, so I talked
about voice like one thing that um,
right now if you're like a sophisticated
user of of of Codex and you know any
other coding agent is you sort of have
gotten used to a little bit of the
clunkiness, right? So you know you have
to manage skill files and you know this
is like a way to sort of like teach it
stuff but it's also I think a lot of
people have realized it's kind of like
hard to maintain over time. Um the
memory is sort of like a thing but it
doesn't always remember uh everything
like if you if you have sub agents you
have to care about sub agents and it's
like sort of like constructs a little
network and the illusion kind of gets
broken into v in in in at various parts
um when you interact with it. And really
what you want is just something that
deeply understands you, understands your
goals, understands your day-to-day,
understands what you know your team is
up to as well. And then optimally is
sort of like reacts and also is
proactive uh and just helps you in your
day-to-day
>> and doesn't break that illusion right of
like that's this perfect little partner
uh that you have and so that's what
we're uh working towards. Another thing
that you know you realize when you have
very very powerful models is that your
laptop kind of becomes a constraint in
and by itself. um you know the amount of
work that you can do on a laptop it was
designed for humans right so it's
designed roughly to be able to absorb
the amount of work that you know you can
produce or you know how fast you can
type and how fast you could think you
know how many applications you need open
all these things are human constraints
um the model doesn't have the same
constraints the model can you know for
example handle you know a 100
applications opened at the same time
perfectly fine you know maybe in the
future and so in terms of access to
resources is it's very clear that you
know models of the future will need
access to more than the resources of
your laptop. Do you I mean I I'm
guessing you're talking about cloud
agents and and all of a sudden like you
know when you have things like ultraast
which we're going to talk about in a
little bit when you have token speeds
that are 10 I think 14 is the the stated
number 10 14 times faster than what fast
is um the the bandwidth changes or sorry
the bandwidth constraint changes uh the
CPU now becomes the bandwidth like
literally tool calls
>> network tool any kind of overhead in the
stack becomes the the limiting factor.
But then you know you can compensate by
doing multiple things uh concurrently
as well. And so you can you can think
about you know having like maybe you
know exploring on one end writing tests
as well compiling uh you know testing a
new hypothesis like all at once. And so
then you're not then you're you're
you're shifting the bottleneck around
because you know you're able to do more
uh concurrently and then you know the
model can like sort of like think very
efficiently and very quickly through it.
>> With current token speeds I find myself
kicking off 10 15 agents in parallel and
that becomes a pretty significant
cognitive overhead for me to do that
context switching and just constantly
cuz you're kicking it off and you can
expect 30 45 minutes before my task
comes back. Now with ultra fast speed
that workflow changes significantly and
I don't think I would be able to have 10
or 15 agents and that might be a good
thing. Maybe it's three or four at a
time. How do you see the the workflow of
a solo developer changing over time?
>> Yeah. So I think managing your attention
and being much more, you know, friendly
to your attention is something that we
care a lot about. Like after all, like
we're trying to build for humans. We're
trying to be like
>> the build the technology that's the most
empowering for humans and that requires
building around you know your ability to
multitask and you know how do you want
to manage your attention and do you want
something brought up now or is it better
to bring it up in 30 minutes um and then
when you have ultra fast speeds combined
you know maybe with voice is like
suddenly you're like okay you know like
this thing can operate at the same speed
if not faster than you and so you stay
in the flow you get to ideulate you get
to see prototypes, you know, like you
get to build little reports like in real
time and that, you know, sort of like
that just feels really good. Um,
suddenly you're like, oh yeah, like what
I was doing before, multitasking like 10
agents, it's like I don't want to really
go back to that.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, and so we're trying to bring that
sort of experience that is just really
natural but also feels built for you,
you know, where you don't have to adapt.
The technology adapts to you. So there's
been a number of I guess agentic coding
techniques discussed over the last few
months. Loops was popular, still is
popular. Now I'm hearing about graphs.
Are are these all techniques to just
allow the solo developer to manage or be
friendly to their to their attention as
you said? I like that term.
>> Yeah. So I I think about two different
categories of of problems. It's like the
first one is building the very best
personal AGI or the personal agent that
will be in the flow with you proactive
raise important new ideas uh when it can
find some be very very efficient at
doing exactly what you want. It doesn't
matter whether it's a technical problem
or you know it's just more like research
or advice like it can do it all and it's
like super super tailored to you. This
is like a very important thing and it's
like deeply rooted in like you know the
understanding of you as a human, you as
like an individual that is unique.
That's one category of problem like
we're pushing super hard on that. The
other category of problem is like
full-on automation. Um you know where
you're more building intelligent systems
that can take care of like a very
complex process. You know maybe
something that did require you know does
require intelligence and seems like very
complex. for example, you know, going
and looking at production logs and
automatically doing performance
optimizations
or looking at regressions and
automatically patching them. In cyber
security, we're seeing this as well
where it's like you have, you know,
something you have a scanner that comes
up with a vulnerability like can you
automatically patch it and reduce the
window um where you have that open
vulnerability to like almost zero
>> with without a human in those loops
>> without a human in the loop or like you
know very very minimal where you know
you only need to approve
>> uh a high risk action and it's like
mostly an automated system
>> but it's also not that much you it's not
as important for you to be in direct
control of it.
>> Okay.
>> Um and then
so I want to slightly change topics and
you know chat GPT and codeex have been
on this merge path
>> over the last few months. So I I guess
first I just wanted to ask you how's
that been going like how does it feel
internally? What's the feedback you've
been getting from your customers?
>> Um it's it's really been a boon. Uh so
the feedback we had initially was like
why why do you merge them? It's like you
know do you really have to do it? And
it's like well the the future the our
future models want us to be merged. So
um you know we're we're just going to do
it because it is the simple and proper
thing to do where we're building this
very personal super capable agent that
can help you in all sorts of ways. This
is the same this is going to be the same
technology under the hood. Um it's the
same harness. It's the same way that we
think about it. It's like highly
multimodal, you know, voice first, uh,
super efficient and and it doesn't
matter if you're trying to code or not.
Like this this agent is capable of it
all. And it's like the high it's like
the most efficient at it. And then the
interface that you want is like it
should tailor itself to your needs. If
you shouldn't decide like you know I'm a
coder, I want a coder interface or like
I'm not technical, I want a nontechnical
interface. It's like there's a spectrum
of people like you know we come up with
labels of like a software engineer, a
designer like you know these are just
human concepts that we have invented to
deal with abstractions because the
reality is too complex for us to handle.
But individuals are like they're
individual they have their own they're
somewhere on the spectrum and so we're
trying to build the perfect interface
that adapts for everyone. It doesn't
matter if you're technical or not. It's
just like it adapts like based on your
specific indiv individuality. So that's
why we went and we did this.
>> But uh does that mean inevitably it's
going to end up with a singular
interface? No drop down selecting
between products and it it's kind of
wild to think that my mom might use the
same exact interface as me and then
obviously it'll customize to my needs.
Maybe I'll need more information if I'm
doing more sophisticated work. Uh but
like what is the end state for you?
>> That's right. It's it's the same thing.
Um so you and your mom will you know use
the same thing. Uh it will be your
personal AGI. You will have very
different kinds of tasks and utility
that you get from it. You will connect
it to different tools in your life. You
will bring different ideas, different
needs. Uh and then it will continue to
tailor itself to maximally benefit you.
Okay.
>> Uh and it will, you know, do so with
your friends and with everyone else.
>> So I I want to go back to something you
said. You used the word illusion a
couple times in that kind of end state.
What is the that perfect illusion for
the the typical user? Like what what
like if you can envision us a few years
from now, what does the interaction
between AI and a human look like?
>> Yeah, it's um to me it's something that
is very very tailored to to to humans.
Um and this this is why large language
models are also a success. It's like
it's it's it's natural language. Natural
language. It's like it's a human
concept, right? Uh so, you know, we're
used to speaking to each other. Like,
you know, if you write me a letter
tomorrow, I'll be able to read it.
>> Um you know, it's like we we know each
other quite a bit now. So, uh you know,
it's like I will be able to sort of
decipher like a little bit of the
emotion or, you know, maybe a little bit
of the nuance behind the letter if you
wrote me a letter. Um and all of that is
is deeply human. So the technology that
we're building is, you know, rooted in
in humanity and rooted in, you know, the
way that humans communicate and get
things done. Um, and there shouldn't
really be a thing where, you know,
you're like, "Oh, you misunderstood me
because, you know, you didn't quite
decipher the nuance in, you know, my
tone or you didn't quite understand the
text, you know, how I meant it." It's
like that's that's um that's something
that we're trying to avoid. And so we're
trying to very much to not have you
adapt, but have the technology just like
be perfectly sort of um created to
um to be like a natural extension of how
humans already act in the world.
>> When I think about communication between
humans, so much of it is non-verbal.
just the way I move my hands, the facial
movements and like h how much of that do
you see in the future being sensed by
artificial intelligence or or read by
artificial intelligence maybe through
vision. Is that even important? Because
what you're describing now is text only.
And for those of us who grew up online,
we're very used to communicating over
text and you know adding subtleties to
that text to convey what we really mean
tone. Um, but like h is it still
important to have AI be able to read our
facial expressions, our hand gestures,
and so on?
>> I think so. Um, so when when when I
think about the future of what we're
building, it's it's very ambient. It's
very natural. Mhm.
>> Um if you know tomorrow uh or like you
know later I go I go to my office and I
write something on the whiteboard and I
have an idea it's like it it should be
capable of you know being there as well
and like you know understanding or you
know maybe I tell it like you know hey
it's just like you know what about this
thing and you know and then we just have
a natural conversation just over voice
>> like since we we shipped the new chat
voice like the it's it's really taken
off. So it's like the amount of users
that interact with LGBT just through
voice is growing very fast right now.
And uh this is this is I think the
lesson is like every time you sort of
like lean into something that is more
natural like humans just choose the the
path of least resistance. You know as
you said it's like typing on a little
box like you know it's just like it's
natural maybe for some of us but not for
for everyone. And it's like definitely
when you get something that is just like
a little bit easier, a little bit
better. like you know you tend to just
go and use that and stuff.
>> Yeah. Okay. I first of all
congratulations. I saw that you posted
this morning. Codeex reached 20 million
users.
I've seen the graph and and you know for
a while it was like this and then all of
a sudden it's vertical. So
congratulations. I want to talk a little
bit about that competition with
anthropic because of course you know a
lot of people think OpenAI Anthropic
these are the two major competitors in
the industry right now. There was a
period of time in which Anthropic was
kind of sucking all the oxygen out of
the room, right? They were really
dominating and then all of a sudden
something changed. Uh so first of all,
what's your read on the market today?
>> Yeah, really right now we're focused on
building the most capable models,
building models that are highly highly
efficient and then taking a lot of pride
in building products for everyone. Um
and I this is something that I think
open AI does uh really well is caring
about the world and caring how about you
know how we are taking this very very
powerful technology and like putting in
the hands of as many people as possible
and this is what you know we did as well
like with merging codeex and chatbt. It
was like this desire of like we have
this we have this technology we we we
can make it safer we can make it easier
to to use uh for everyone whether you
know you're like uh a product manager a
designer in sales marketing coms all of
that like you know you should be able to
use all of it and then uh just very very
quickly you know distributed through
charge like where we have a ton of users
already and so that's been that's been
really driving you know this growth
Earth as well that you mentioned and I
don't tend to look at the competition
that much like I really look at you know
what can we do uniquely well and what
are our values and like you know how do
we maximally accelerate towards that.
>> Okay. Um I want to maybe just dig a tiny
bit more into that because I I know
you're not thinking about anthropic all
that much but a lot of other people do
and they're they're thinking about okay
which product do I believe in? which
product do I want to give my $2200
to? Um, when you look at the market
position and the branding and the tone
from OpenAI and just the way that it
interacts with developers, with the
broader audience, how do you see that
comparing to the way that Anthropic
does?
>> Yeah, I think maybe again like what I
care a lot about is like the community
building for the world, like bringing
everyone along. Um I think you know you
can feel that in the way that we we we
are super transparent about things like
we take a lot of ideas from the
community. It's just like it's also so
much fun to be honest. Um you know
because we get so much energy from it as
well. Um and then this technology that
we're building we're not building it
just for ourselves like we're not just
building it to accelerate um just to
open AI. It's like it's super important.
the the mission is super important and
therefore it's like you know this is
where we also get our energy from um and
so it just feels to me it feels like
very grounded uh it feels fun and then
good things happen as a result of that
>> well let's talk about some of those good
things I want to talk about the resets
for a second to that's kind of like I
know it's like what everybody is you
know kind of following your every tweet
because of this um specifically like
again looking at that growth curve of
codeex how maybe this is a silly
question. How much do those resets how
much of it is a boon towards marketing
and growth or is it was it just like
goodwill for the developer community?
>> I think maybe it it's counterintuitive,
but OpenAI is a very it's a place where
you can just do things. Um and so it
just felt right initially to compensate
when we were iterating and breaking
things or you know maybe we had
misconfigured something and it wasn't
quite as good as we wanted and so it's
like hey you know thank you for trying
this product like we know like we're
trying very hard to build it. it's like
it's early days. Um you know here's some
extra usage because you know we happen
to break it you know for like 30 minutes
and you know we understand this is like
really important and rely on it and you
know thank you for being a user and so
this is how it started um and you know
this is how I still treat it. It's like
if we break it um or if the experience
is suboptimal and we don't fully
understand why it's like you know we
will we will compensate for that. we
will reset um the usage limits and then
you know it turned into like quite the
thing obviously there's a whole reset
button now and like but there isn't
really a whole a lot of scrutiny behind
it. It's like there it's not done in
partnership with like marketing or or
finance. It's just like I can press the
button whenever I want um whenever it
feels right. Um and we have these
principles that you know we're we're
trying to build something amazing and
when it is not it's like you know we
will make up for it.
>> Yeah. I I still think there's a piece of
it that really has built so much
goodwill in the community and maybe has
contributed to the growth at least in a
small part. I
>> I think caring for your users does does
a lot, right? So, um I think you can pay
lip service and say that you care or you
know you can be like we actually care
and like you know if we break it like
you know hey really sorry about it you
know it's like here's here's like how we
make up for it.
>> It kind of reminds me of Amazon's return
policy. It's like if you're not happy in
any sense, go ahead and send it back.
And and it you're kind of building that
same culture or that same perception of
open AI. It's like, hey, if we make a
mistake, go ahead, use those tokens
again or or you know, have here's a
here's a fresh batch of tokens for you.
I Yeah, I really appreciate it. So,
>> and then there's also, you know, good
moments where we just want to celebrate
and mark the moment. And it's just
there'sn't really something that we can
give that is more meaningful
>> um you know, at times like we always
ship new features. is we will ship them
as broadly as we can. Um but something
to share with the entire community. It's
like you know hey go explore this new
thing like you know just like you
haven't used ultra yet you know here's
some extra usage like you know try it
>> and and I heard there's an actual
physical button now.
>> Yes there is.
>> Yeah. Okay. You'll have to show me that
after. [laughter]
>> I will show it to you. It's like very
very cool.
>> But with all of these resets like you
can really only do that if you've done
significant compute capacity planning.
like you have to have enough compute to
give all of these resets. And I I want
to start to talk a little bit about
self-improvement because um like
speaking of capacity, a few weeks ago, I
think it was a few weeks ago, there was
this uh article you put out and it
stated Soul had optimized Luna
efficiency. You dropped the price of
Luna by 80%. There was also a price drop
for Terra as well. How much of a an uh
efficiency gain were you able to eke out
of Luna versus how much of it is like we
just did really great compute capacity
planning and and we can just drop the
price like our margins are great and we
can still we want people to use it. So
like how much of it were algorithmic
gains versus um strategic planning? We
planned uh compute like way ahead. You
know, I think if you look back two
years, I think OpenAI was um kind of
questioned for why, you know, there was
like so much investment in compute. Um
>> one of those crazy good bets.
>> Yes. uh and then now we're very happy to
have it like a very large fraction of
the computers used for research where we
invest in our future and you know ever
ever better models and then also like
the the efficiency of the models that we
have and then the amazing thing that's
happening is like when we push the
frontier of capability for like the most
advanced models that we have then we can
use these models in order to figure out
very very quickly how to serve or how to
restructure uh or re-engineer our stack
in order to gain very significant
efficiency or performance gains. So we
haven't just improved this is something
that we will publish on as well. We
haven't just improved the the cost
efficiency, but we have also improved
the speed efficiency. You know, outside
of ultraast, things have gotten
significantly faster over time. They
have
>> like if you plot it, it's like, you
know, the amount of um just the amount
of speed that you get now is like, you
know, roughly
>> 60% faster than, you know, what it used
to be like 3 months ago. And this is
just like we're we're just going after
every part of the stack and just really
making sure that we design it and and
engineering it optimally for the kind of
workloads that we have. Uh and so you
know and the most powerful models that
that we have are the ones like you know
just really that make it capable for us
to do it you know with a very small
team. And so the majority of like what
when when whenever we come up with like
very significant efficiency gains and
cost efficiency like our commitment is
to just really to keep things at the
frontier of performance cost um and to
just also like you know just not just
pocket you know that uh interesting gain
and just make it something that we know
we share with our customers we share
with our users and that's what we did
with with Luna. How how do you what do
the discussions look like internally
where you're trying to decide compute
allocation towards uh researching new
models, efficiency gains on existing
models, inference like what does that
tension look like internally?
Um the we we we we usually look at
things um from from first principles and
we have like an allocation for research,
we have an allocation for um for product
and then within product we make
different kinds of trade-offs but this
one was u almost not even a trade-off
because uh the the efficiency gains were
there. Um so you know we were pretty
much like able to use like the same
compute envelope in order to you know
serve this like very very significant
increase in throughput.
>> Yeah. So when I mean when I saw the blog
post a few months ago prior to the price
drop blog post where you guys were
talking about one model training the
next model or helping kind of optimize
the next model. Um then you see these
efficiency gains that were achieved by
soul looking at how Luna was running. Uh
I you know it seems to me like recursive
self-improvement in the very early
innings. What what are your thoughts
there? Is that what is happening? Um
yeah, I think recursive self-improvement
is uh it's obviously a huge topic right
now and it's most often uh I think
applied to to research um and you know
models developing other models but what
we are seeing a ton of success with is
you know using those models to develop
the infrastructure that is on the
critical path of using those models you
know which is also a form of recursive
self-improvement. It's all one big
system.
>> Inference stack, you know, the the the
harder like the opt the the the the
kernels, uh CUDA kernels that we use. Um
developing new products and new ways to
interact with those models that are more
efficient. You know, you talked about
cloud agents. It's like if we if we
really crack uh cloud agents, it's like
suddenly you become much more productive
as well. It's like is that a form of
like recursive self-improvement because
then you know you have a better ability
to get the utility from them. I I think
it is in some sense, but it's much more
um you know infrastructure and then you
know being able to then take that and
then point it back at itself.
>> Yeah.
>> And so of course like we're doing that
like if we were not doing that um I
think that would be pretty silly.
>> Can you talk a little bit about So as
we're on the topic of recursive
self-improvement uh OpenAI Sam Alman
talked about pausing the absolute
frontier of RL right now I believe. Um
can you talk a little bit about that?
Like what was that decision like? And I
know we talked about the hugging face
incident briefly, but like what went
into that decision? What does that look
like? How did those discussions go?
>> Yeah, this is this is something very
much within within research where
there's um OpenAI has always uh been
able to invest uh its resources where it
matters most. Um and as we increase the
capabilities of our models, it is very
obvious that you know the the alignment
and the safety aspect of it is you know
ever more important. And so having uh
having tremendous um amount of
investment there uh is is a very natural
thing for OpenAI and like something that
OpenAI is very committed to. And so
we're seeing um a huge surge uh in
investment um on this and also the
uh the pause was sort of like necessary
to uh allow like the teams and the
individuals like just really understand
and harden all parts of the system uh to
then you know ensure that you know we
could we could restart training uh with
you know like full full full command and
this is something that you know I
believe OpenAI will always continue to
do like when when necessary. I've I've
not seen
I've not seen us internally not able to
make such decisions like very
efficiently.
>> Was there like some set goal in place
where it was very clear you needed to
reach this point before unpausing or was
it hey we'll know it when we see it?
Yeah, this is this is something that
sits um within within the the safety
team and uh they they very much this is
like very much a a debate and sort of
like a discovery process as you go. Um
but then they did reach uh a fairly
clear set of principles uh that you know
when reached like you know we we would
be in a good position. I want to go back
to uh ultra fast mode that I think
people don't appreciate what that kind
of speed unlocks and so let's start with
what use cases are you doing are you
using internally that were not possible
prior to having those kind of tokens per
second.
>> We see it used a lot when the stakes are
high. Um so for example when you have um
when we have an outage um the incident
commander and the response team gets
access to ultra fast um because every
every second is you know matters. Um so
high stake um high stake scenarios like
just really weren't you know using ultra
fast. Also um it's it's kind of like a
fun thing where uh teams which are like
either working on something very
critical or believe they are working on
something very critical will always
request ultra fast as well. Um
>> does pets fall under that?
>> Uh pets.
>> Yeah, pets. [laughter]
>> Pets is not quite hyperritical. But I
love I love my pet. It's always on my
screen. uh like when you walk around uh
you see like you know people's pets on
their screen and like also when they
they dial in into the the video call
it's just like it always like I think
it's very delightful and it brings me
joy every time I see it but uh pet is
not quite critical right now [laughter]
um we we do maintain it um and we take
good care of our pets but uh say you
know someone is working uh on like a a
new idea they have and they're like you
know hey it's just like you know I
really think this could be like
something special and we have to try it
but like you know we have to make a
decision on Monday on like know whether
we include this in dev day or not and
it's like okay just like you know of
course you know use ultra fast um people
have different kinds of preferences on
uh whether whether they like to be you
know mono threaded as we talked about or
multitask a lot for folks who like to
multitask a lot you don't benefit as
much from ultraast
>> but some people
>> it's like don't like to change context
all the time. Um,
>> where do you fall on that spectrum?
>> I I have ADHD, so I like I context
switch like all the time.
>> It's funny cuz I also have ADHD and I
actually don't want to context switch
all the time. That's really hard for me.
I want to focus on two to three and and
that's why I was so excited about ultra
fast. That's fascinating that you're the
opposite there.
>> You know, I thrive in context switching
and making lots of little decisions. Um
but you know sometimes I do want to just
stay focused on like one thing and then
ultra fast is just delightful because it
just keeps you just right there in the
flow.
>> The thing with ultra fast uh that you
know we we it it works amazingly well
when there's not that many tool calls
involved or it's like a lot of
generation of context. So for example,
if you're trying to prototype um a
website or a video game and you know you
just need to it to write like a lot of
code um then it will do it so so quickly
right you know 10 times more quickly but
if it's a lot of tool calls like the
overhead is in like somewhere else in
the network or you know somewhere else
in the agent trajectory then you know
you'll only feel like a 3x or 4x speed
up.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and you'll not get that four like
full 14x. So I I know OpenAI employees
get unlimited tokens and I can imagine
if I had unlimited tokens I would always
set it to max thinking 5.6 solar
whatever the latest model is it
>> and I would think kind of similarly I
would always want ultra fast on it's
like when when cost isn't on my mind I'm
like okay max it out.
>> Is that how it is internally?
>> We don't we don't give ultra fast to
everyone like we reserve a lot of our
capacity for external users and
customers.
>> Yeah. Um, so O OpenAI employees have the
ability and the capacity to gobble up
all of it, right? So gobble up like all
of our production GPUs, all of ultra
fast is like uh you know we would use
all of it but you know we don't like we
sort of um we restrict it in a way uh
where you know like we we we look at you
know how much is reasonable for us.
Yeah. So that you know we use it so that
we understand the product as well so
that we keep improving it so that we
benefit from you know recursive
self-improvement but um the the vast
majority is like reserved for customers.
>> Okay. Yeah that's good. Thanks. Um uh
[laughter]
what latency sensitive use cases outside
of open AI are you most excited about
that gets unlocked by that kind of that
kind of speed?
>> It's interesting. It's just like really
one one thing that I'm very excited
about in general is um nontext
interactions. So um can you can you like
sort of operate on a shared canvas? Can
you create things? Can you do can you
generate you know ideas and different uh
can you generate different images and
then select one and like so like know
choose your adventure uh and and and
then you know have a very quick mockup
of a prototype that then you can steer
um you know like in real time either
through voice or through text and then
you sort of like just see it right
there. Um it's like this very creative
process which I think these speeds
allow. um where you know like as as an
engineer sometimes you know you're just
like sort of like you sit back and
you're like oh I need to design this
whole system I need to think about it
the trade-offs the requirements but like
you know maybe you know you can just
create it in one minute and see like how
it actually does um and then sort of
like be more like in the flow and like
you know in it things better and I think
these speeds a lot
>> yeah and so I'm assuming the ultra fast
price is going to be significantly
higher than than kind of normal speeds
do Do you think ultra fast speeds are
going to become the standard or are they
always going to have a premium price
point?
>> Um, that's interesting. So, I think the
the the same way as technology usually
goes, I think it will become like more
broadly and you know broader and broader
accessibility over time. Um, the speeds
at which like agents get things done
like you know will continue to improve
like we're seeing massive improvements
like month after month. Um this is not
just the inference speed. This is also
the just how token efficient the models
are. Like soul is like significantly
more token efficient than terra. Next
model will be significantly more
efficient uh token efficient than than
soul as you might expect. And we always
pushing on that. And so things just get
faster over time. Inference hardware
like you know everything you know just
like we continue to uh innovate there
and it gets faster. So I do think in you
know maybe a year or two these speeds
will become you know maybe if not the
default like very close to the default
but then I do also think you know you
will always have like the one tier up um
where you know you can always use more
hardware you can always do different
trade-offs that are like more costly um
but that just kind of give you something
something extra.
>> So TBO the the last question I usually
like to end on uh is is for a broader
audience. There are a lot of people out
there who are quite nervous about AI,
whether it's uh job automation,
environmental impact, um or just kind of
this this thing that's happening. It's
and it feels quite foreign. What words
of encouragement would you give to the
the broader audience?
>> Yeah. So we we we really build for the
world with with Chhatri and we are very
very much um
investing in you know how efficient it
is and you know this is directly aligned
with like you know broad access and
broad utility that we provide. So the
cheaper it is you know to serve like you
know the more the more you can do with
it um the more you get out of it in your
daily life and it has gotten very very
efficient like if you look at uh you
know Luna for example like it's it's a
much smaller model it is u it is
incredibly efficient but like if you
rewind six six months ago it would have
sat at the frontier.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and you look at the cost of Luna
right it's like you know it's like it's
it's
>> it's crazy cheap.
>> It's it's um it's phenomenal. Right.
It's like a kind of
>> You just did that thing with Reply.
You're giving it away for free now.
>> They're giving Yeah. They're It's just
like on on on on um in this free mode,
right? Um which is like wow. You know,
it's like this access to incredible
intelligence will become like
ubiquitous. Um and it's only possible
when you push, you know, you push the
efficiency like you know like month
after month after month, year after
year. And so I think you know whatever
was like you know is a frontier now is
like you know will become like way way
cheaper to run in six months. And so
this is this is like my uh sort of you
know this is how I would answer this
question is just
uh technology has a way to become like
you know very very efficient over time.
Um and we're very focused on like you
know very broad access and we're
optimizing for you know the utility that
you get out of it directly. How about
for people who are apprehensive to even
try AI for the first time? Like what
what are you telling them and and how
how can you paint them picture a vision
of the future in which AI is is helping
the world?
>> Yes. Um I think it's you don't have to
look very far like Judge PT helps um
people in very personal and deep ways
like a lot of um a lot of our users use
it for help in writing but also like you
know for personal advice or you know
medical advice like we we launched um
health and finance and you know I I I I
use them super regularly and uh I I feel
like I get like a lot of uh support that
I otherwise like you know it would be
hard for me to get and it allows me for
example to be more informed when I go
see my doctor. And so you don't you
don't need to go very far um you know to
kind of see the utility that it can
provide. Just I think you know talking
to others and then you know getting
inspired by you know how others use it
and benefit from it is like a great way
to you know just maybe um like start
considering how you could benefit from
it.
>> Well Tibo, thank you so much. Thank you
appreciate your time.